《马达加斯加》
Surprise!
惊喜吧!
Alex. Do not interrupt me when I'm daydreaming.
亚里克斯! 我做白日梦的时候不要打扰我!
When a zebra's in the zone, leave him alone.
当斑马在动物园里时 别理他
Come on, Marty. Just wanted to wish you a happy birthday.
马蒂 只是想祝你生日快乐!
Hey, man, thanks.
嘿伙计 谢谢
Hey, I got something stuck in my teeth.
我塞牙了
It's driving me crazy. Can you help me? Please?
真难受! 你能帮帮我吗? 拜托?
You came to the right place, my friend.
你来对地方了 我的朋友
Dr. Marty, D.D.S. , is in the house.
马蒂医生时刻准备着!
Please hop on top of my sterilized examination table, if you may.
请跳上我已经消毒的检查台 如果你还能行的话
- I don't see anything. - It's on the left.
- 我什么也没看到 - 在左边
Oh, sorry.
哦 对不起
Okay, just don't talk with your mouth full.
好吧 好吧 别张嘴讲话
Right here. What the heck is this doing in there?
这里 这个东西在里面干什么?
Happy birthday!
生日快乐!
Aw, hey, thanks, man.
谢谢!
You put it in behind the tooth. You all right.
它在牙后面 你没事了
These aren't even on the shelf yet. Here. Check it out.
还没有上市呢 这个 看看
- Look at that. Ooh! Look at that. - Look at that. It's snowing.
- 看看那个 看看 - 看看 在下雪哟
Ten years old, huh? A decade.
十年了 哈? 十年!
Double digits. The big 1-0.
两位数 1-0
You don't like it?
你不喜欢吗?
- No, no, it's great. - You hate it.
- 不 不 礼物很棒! - 你不喜欢它
I should've gotten you the Alex alarm clock. That's the big seller.
我应该给你亚里克斯闹钟就好了 就是那个卖得更好的
No, no, no. The present's great, really.
不 不 礼物很棒 真的
It's just that another year's come and gone
只是一年又一年
and I'm still doing the same old thing.
我仍然重复着同样的生活
"Stand over here. Trot over there. Eat some grass. Walk back over here. "
"站在这 站在那 吃点草 再走回来"
- I see your problem. - Maybe I should go to law school.
- 我了解你的问题 - 也许我应该去上法学院
You just need to break out of that boring routine.
你只是需要从那乏味的日常生活中解脱
- How? - Throw out the old act.
- 怎么办? - 不要老一套
Who knows what you'll do. Make it up as you go along.
冲破禁锢 谁知道你要干什么呢!
Ad lib. Improvise. On the fly. Boom, boom, boom.
现编现演! 增加一些临时的即兴表演!
- Really? - You know, make it fresh.
- 真的? - 你知道 保持新鲜感!
Fresh, huh? Okay. I could do fresh.
新鲜感? 好 我可以做些不同的事
Works for me.
对我有用哟
Here come the people, Marty. I love the people.
参观的人来了马蒂 哦 我爱人群!
It's fun people fun time!
是娱乐者的娱乐时间了!
Let's go, Gloria! Up and at 'em. We're open!
快点格洛瑞尔! 上下然后张嘴!
What day is it?
今天星期几?
It's Friday. Field trip day.
星期五 郊游日
Yes, it's field trip day. Let's get up and go...
对 今天是郊游日 快 起来开工啦!
... in ten more minutes.
再多睡10分钟
Come on!
快点!
Melman, Melman, Melman! Melman, Melman, Melman!
梅尔曼 梅尔曼 梅尔曼! 梅尔曼 梅尔曼 梅尔曼!
Wake up! Rise and shine! It's another fabulous morning in the Big Apple.
醒醒! 太阳晒屁股啦! 又一个美好的纽约清晨!
Let's go.
快起来!
- Not for me. I'm calling in sick. - What?
- 我不觉得 我病了 - 怎么了?
I found another brown spot on my shoulder. Right here. See?
我肩膀上发现又一块褐斑 就在这 你看见了吗?
Right there. You see?
看? 就在那! 你看见了吗?
Melman, you know it's all in your head. Hm?
梅尔曼 你知道这都是你幻想出来的
Let's go! Come on!
我们走! 快点!
Phil! Wake up, you filthy monkey.
菲尔 醒醒 你这个滑稽的猴子
Oh, I'm going to be fresh.
哦我要保持新鲜感
Straight out the ground. Tasty fresh! Freshalicious.
直截了当 尝试新鲜 新鲜
Ziploc fresh.
斑马的新鲜
Ladies and gentlemen, children of all ages,
女士们先生们 各位小朋友
the Central Park Zoo proudly presents:
中央动物园骄傲地介绍:
Show them the cat. Who's the cat?
给他们看那狮子! 谁是狮子?
The king of New York City.
纽约的国王
Alex the lion.
狮子亚里克斯
It's showtime.
演出时间到
Roar!
咆哮!
Gather around, people. Big show about to start.
大家聚一聚 重大表演要开始了!
Check out the zebra taking care of biz. That's right.
看看斑马的加农炮 没错!
Just smile and wave, boys.
微笑着招手 伙计们
Smile and wave.
微笑着招手
Kowalski, progress report.
科娃斯基 任务报告
We're 500 feet from the main sewer line.
我们离公园主干线还有500英尺
- And the bad news? - We've broken our last shovel.
- 坏消息呢? - 我们最后一把铲子折了
Right.
好
Rico, you're on litter patrol. We need shovels.
里科 你负责侦查 我们需要铲子
And find more Popsicle sticks. We don't want to risk another cave-in.
和更多棒棒糖棍 我们不能再重新挖一次了
And me, skipper?
那我呢 船长?
I want you to look cute and cuddly, private.
我要你看上去可爱讨喜 二等兵
Today we're going to blow this dump.
今天我们要离开这水坝
Come here. Come here. Come on, penguin.
到这儿来 过来这里 来 小企鹅
Yeah! You don't see that on Animal Planet.
耶! 你没在动物星球看过这样的表演吧!
Ha-ha.
哈-哈
Well, show's over, folks. Thanks for coming.
表演结束了! 感谢光临!
I hope you thought it was fresh.
我希望你们觉得新鲜!
I'll be here all week.
我整个星期都在
In fact, I'll be here for my whole life.
事实上我一生中
Three hundred and sixty-five days a year,
每一年365天我都在
including Christmas, Hanukkah, Halloween, Kwanzaa.
包括圣诞 万圣节!
Please don't forget to never spay or neuter your pets.
别忘了阉割你们的宠物
And tip your cabbie, because he's broke.
还有给出租司机小费 因为他破产了
You, quadruped. Sprechen sie Englisch?
你 黑白的家伙 会说英语吗?
I sprechen.
我会
- What continent is this? - Manhattan.
- 这是什么国家? - 曼哈顿
Hoover Dam! We're still in New York.
该死! 我们还在纽约
Abort. Dive! Dive! Dive.
任务取消 下潜 下潜 下潜
Hey. You in the tux. Wait a minute.
嘿! 穿晚礼服的家伙! 等等!
What are you guys doing?
你们在干什么?
We're digging to Antarctica.
我们要挖去南极洲
Ant-who-tica?
南什么州?
Can you keep a secret, my monochromatic friend?
你能保密吗 我的色盲朋友?
Do you ever see any penguins running free around New York City?
你以前见过企鹅随便在纽约溜达吗?
Of course not. We don't belong here. It's just not natural.
当然没有 我们不属于这里 这里不是大自然
This is all some kind of whacked-out conspiracy.
这都是一些怪人的阴谋
We're going to the wide-open spaces of Antarctica.
我们要去南极洲的广阔空间
To the wild.
去野外!
The wild? You could actually go there?
野外? 你们真的能到吗?
That sounds great.
听上去不错
Hey, hold up. Where is this place? Tell me where it is.
嘿! 等等! 那是什么地方? 告诉我那是什么地方!
You didn't see anything.
你什么也没看到
Right?
对吧?
Yes, sir.
是 长官
I'm sorry. No, sir.
抱歉 没看到 长官
For his final appearance of the day,
今天的表演
the king of New York City.
纽约市之王
Alex the lion.
狮子亚里克斯
Roar!
咆哮!
Thank you. Thank you very much.
谢谢! 非常感谢!
You guys are great. You're a great crowd. Give yourselves a hand.
你们真好 给我点什么 谢谢
Thank you. Oh. Thank you.
谢谢! 哦 谢谢!
Oh! Well. Thank you.
哦! 很好 谢谢
Oh, that's too kind. Too kind.
哦 你们太好人了 你们真好
Underpants!
内裤!
Everybody get home safe. Hey! Check out my Web site.
平安到家 嘿! 去我的网站看看
Twenty-four hour Alex Cam. Watch me sleep.
24小时开着的亚里克斯摄像头 可以看我睡觉
This is the life.
这就是生活
That's the spot.
就是这里
Oh! I'm in heaven.
哦 我身处天堂
- Ooh, it's Marty's birthday. - Just rip it open.
- 哇哦 今天是马蒂的生日! - 拆开 拆开吧!
- What is it? - Come on. Open it up. What you got?
- 这是什么? 这是什么? - 快点 拆开! 你收到什么?
A thermometer.
耶! 体温计!
Thanks. I love it, Melman. I love it.
谢谢 我喜欢 梅尔曼 我喜欢!
I wanted to give you something personal. That was my first rectal thermometer.
是啊 我想给你些私人的东西 你知道这是我第一支直肠体温计
- Mother... - I'll miss that bad boy.
- 妈呀 呸 呸 呸 - 我会想念那个坏孩子的
Get the cake. Melman, come on.
梅尔曼 把蛋糕拿过来
Happy birthday to you
生日快乐!
You live in a zoo
你住在动物园
You look like a monkey
你看上去像只猴子
And you smell like one too
闻起来也像
I say.
我说
Aw, well, now, you guys are just embarrassing me.
不错 你们真让我难为情!
And yourselves.
还有你们自己!
What? We worked on that all week.
你在说什么? 我们准备了一个星期
Let's go. Let's make a wish, babycakes.
快点 许个愿吧
- What'd you wish for? - Nope. Can't tell you that.
- 快点 你许了什么愿? - 不 不能告诉你
Come on. Tell.
快点 说!
No siree. I'm telling you, it's bad luck.
没戏 我告诉了你们就会被诅咒的
You want some bad luck, I'll blab it out.
你们想走霉运? 那我就说
But if you want to be safe, I'll keep my mouth shut.
但如果你们想没事的话 我就什么都不说
Would you just tell us? What could happen?
啊 马蒂你能告诉我们吗? 我说真的 说了又会怎样?
Okay.
好吧
I wished I could go to the wild!
我希望我能去野外!
The wild? !
野外! 哇哦!
I told you it was bad luck.
我告诉过你们说了会走霉运的!
The wild? Are you nuts?
野外? 你没事吧?
That is the worst idea I've ever heard.
这是我听过的最糟的主意
It's unsanitary.
这样很不卫生
The penguins are going. So why can't l?
企鹅能去 为什么我不能?
The penguins are psychotic.
企鹅是神经病
Come on. Just imagine going back to nature.
想想重回自然的怀抱
Back to your roots. Clean air, wide-open spaces!
回到你的老家 清新的空气 广阔的天地!
I hear there's wide-open spaces in Connecticut.
嗯我听说康涅狄格就很空旷
- Connecticut? - You got to go over to Grand Central.
- 康涅狄格? - 对 你要做的就是穿过中央车站
Then you got to take the Metro-North train... north?
然后上一辆北上的列车 是北吧?
So one could take the train? Just hypothetically.
所以可以搭车过去? 只是想想罢了
Come on. What would Connecticut have to offer us?
马蒂 行了! 康涅狄格能给我们什么啊?
- Lyme disease. - Thank you, Melman.
- 狮子的疾病 - 谢谢 梅尔曼
No, I just want...
不 不 真的我只是
There's none of this in the wild.
野外你肯定不会有这个
This is a highly refined type of food thing
这精致的食物
that you do not find in the wild.
野外不可能找得到
You ever thought there might be more to life than steak, Alex?
你没有想过生命和肉排之外的东西吗 亚里克斯?
He didn't mean that, baby. No, no, no.
他不是那个意思 宝贝 不 不 不
Doesn't it bother you guys that you don't know anything
你们对动物园外的世界一无所知
about life outside this zoo?
不觉得难过吗?
- Nuh-uh. Nope. - Mm-mm.
- 不 - 不
Well, I mean, come on. That's just one subject.
嗯 我是说 这只是个小事
You got a little schmutz right there on your... .
你嘴边有点脏
Thanks, guys. Thanks for the party. It was great.
谢谢 谢谢你们帮我庆祝 很棒!
Really.
真的
What's eating him?
什么让他无精打采?
Maybe you should talk to him. Go over and give him a little pep talk.
也许你该跟他谈谈 亚里克斯 你过去安慰安慰他
Hey, I already gave him a snow globe. I can't top that.
嗨 我已经给了他水晶球了 我还能做什么呢
- Alex. - I can see where this is going.
- 亚里克斯 - 我看你们也无计可施了
It is getting late. I guess I'm going to...
很晚了 我想我要
Come on. He's your best friend.
快点 他是你最好的朋友
All right, all right. Okay.
好吧 好吧 好
- Night, Marty. - Night, Glo.
- 晚安 马蒂! - 晚安 格洛瑞尔
What a day.
今天过得真不错
I mean, I tell you, it just doesn't get any better than this, you know?
我是说 真的我告诉你 不会比现在更好了 你知道吗?
Ooh! It just did. Even the star's out.
真的! 连星星都出来了
Not going to find a star like that in the wild.
我猜野外找不到这样的星星
Helicopter.
直升机
Marty. Buddy. Listen.
马蒂 伙计 听着
Everybody has days when they think the grass might be greener somewhere else.
每个人都会想别处的草比这里的绿
Alex.
亚里克斯
Look at me.
你看我
I'm ten years old. My life is half over.
我已经10岁了 过了半辈子了
And I don't even know if I'm black with white stripes...
而我甚至不知道我是黑底白条
... or white with black stripes.
还是白底黑条的
Marty.
马蒂
I'm thinking of a song.
我想起一首歌
Alex. Please. Not now.
亚里克斯 拜托 不是现在
Oh, yes. It's a wonderful song. I think you're familiar with it.
就是 是首好歌 我想你很熟悉
Oh, no. Oh, no, you don't. No, no, no.
噢不!
I'm not listening.
我不听
Start spreadin' the news
开始广布消息
I don't know you.
我不认识你
I'm leaving today
今天我将离开
- We are a great big part of it - He's funny. Who is that?
- 我们组成了家 - 这家伙真搞笑 他是谁?
Come on. You know you know the words.
快点 你知道 你知道那个词
Two little words.
两个小小的字
New York.
纽约
New York
纽约!
Shut up, shut up, shut up! Hey, I'm sleeping here!
闭嘴! 闭嘴! 我在睡觉!
We're not all nocturnal, you know!
我们可不全是你们所知道的海龟!
I'll knock your "turnal" right off, pal.
我也没给你特权 朋友!
Yeah, you and what army, stripes?
对 你不用跑 你这斑马!
You mess with him, you mess with me, Howard.
你惹他 你就是惹我 胆小鬼!
- You're a bigmouth lion. - See? Mr. Grumpy Stripes.
- 你这头大嘴狮 - 看见了? 坏脾气的斑马先生
We make a great team, the two of us.
我们是一个伟大的团队 我们俩
We sure do. No doubt about it.
当然 毋庸置疑!
So, what are you going to do? Go running off to the wild by yourself?
那你还想干什么? 独自跑到野外去?
- No. - Good.
- 不 - 太好了
You and me. Let's go.
你和我! 我们一起
- What? - The wild.
- 什么? - 野外
Come on. You and me together.
你和我一起!
It's a straight shot down Fifth Avenue to Grand Central.
有条小路从第五大道到中央车站
We'll grab a train, we'll head north.
我们爬上一列火车 一直向北!
We can be back by morning. No one will ever know.
我们早上就能回来 没人会知道!
You're joking. Right?
你说笑的 对吧?
Yeah. I'm joking. Of course I'm joking. Give me a break.
对! 我说笑的 当然是开玩笑! 别逗了
Like we're going to get a train.
你想我们怎么搭火车?
Don't do that. You really had me worried there.
以后别再那样了 你刚才弄得我很担心
Oh, well. I guess I'll hit the sack.
嗯 我想我该睡了
Yeah, me too. I'll need to rest my voice for tomorrow.
对 我也是 为了明天得好好休息嗓子
It's Seniors' Day, you know. Have to roar extra loud.
明天大孩子来 我得叫得更大声些
Give them a little jolt. You know?
给他们点颜色看看! 你知道我在说什么吧?
Good night, AllyAl.
晚安 亚里克斯
They forgot to turn off the ambience again.
他们又忘了关音响!
Don't worry. It's cool.
别担心 没事
You know, I got it.
我来
Much better.
好多了
Come on, now, baby.
来吧 宝贝
My little filet.
我的小肉排
My little filet mignon with a little fat around the edges.
我的边上有点肥肉的菲利牛排
I like that. I like a little fat on my steak.
我喜欢 我喜欢边上有点肥肉的
My sweet, juicy steak. You are a rare delicacy.
我的香甜多汁的牛排 真是极品美味
Alex. Alex. Alex!
亚里克斯 亚里克斯 亚里克斯!
What? What?
怎么了?
You suck your thumb?
你吮拇指?
What is it, Melman?
怎么了 梅尔曼?
Ok! Ok! You know how I have that bladder infection
好吧 好吧 你知道我膀胱发炎
and I have to get up every two hours?
每两个小时就要起夜
I got up to pee and looked over at Marty's pen, which I usually don't do.
我去方便的时候 看了看马蒂的床 我一般不会如此
I don't know why, but I did. And...
我不知道为什么这次我看了
What? What's going on?
怎么了梅尔曼 出什么事了?
It's Marty. He's gone.
是马蒂 他不见了
Gone! What do you mean, "gone"?
不见了? 你什么意思 不见了?
How long has he been working on this?
他挖这个多久了?
Marty!
马蒂!
He wouldn't fit down there.
那洞他进不去
Marty? Marty! Marty!
马蒂? 马蒂! 马蒂!
This doesn't make any sense. Where would he go?
真没道理 他会去哪里?
- Connecticut! - He wouldn't.
- 康涅狄格! - 他不会
Oh, no! What are we going to do?
噢不! 我们该怎么办?
I mean, we got to call somebody!
我们应该 应该找人!
Hello? Get me Missing Animals. And hurry.
哈喽? 给我接走失动物中心! 快!
We've got a lost zebra probably on the way to Connecticut, and we need...
我们有头斑马不见了 可能现在在去康涅狄格的路上 我们需要
- Hello? Hello? - Wait a second.
- 喂? 喂? - 等会儿
- We can't call the people. - What the... ?
- 我们不能找人 - 谁在 ?
They'll be really mad.
他们会非常生气!
It'll get Marty transferred for good. Don't bite the hand that feeds you.
然后把马蒂永远送走! 你不能恩将仇报
Mm-hm, I know that's right.
恩哼 那是对的
We got to go after him. He's not thinking straight.
我们得去追他 他头脑不清
Let's stop him from making the biggest mistake of his life.
我们要阻止他 犯下生命中最大的错误
He's probably out there lost and cold, confused.
他很有可能迷路了 饥寒交迫不知所措
Poor little guy.
可怜的小家伙
Come on.
梅尔曼 快点!
One of us should wait here in case he comes back.
也许我们应该有个人等在这里 万一他回来呢
Not now. This is an intervention. We all got to go.
噢不 不是现在 这事我们一定得管 梅尔曼 我们都要去!
What's the fastest way to Grand Central?
怎么去中央车站最快?
- You should take Lexington. - Melman!
- 你应该走莱克星敦街 - 梅尔曼!
- Okay. "We. " We should take Lexington. - What about Park?
- 好吧 "我们" 我们应该走莱克星敦街 - 那帕克街呢?
No, Park goes two ways. You can't time the lights.
不好 帕克街是双向 红绿灯多
I heard Tom Wolfe is speaking at Lincoln Center.
我听说汤姆伍尔夫在林肯中心演讲
Well, of course we're going to throw poo at him.
那我们当然要去闹场子啦!
We should've taken Park.
我就知道我们应该走帕克街
You sure this is the fastest way to Grand Central Station?
你确定这是去中央车站最快的路?
I don't know! That's what Melman said.
我不知道 是梅尔曼说的!
Hey. Hey, you, guys.
嘿伙计们!
That room has some nifty little sinks you can wash up in, and look!
那个房间让你可以洗 还有 看!
Free mints!
免费薄荷糖!
This isn't a field trip.
我们不是来郊游
This is an urgent mission to save Marty from throwing his life away.
是来救马蒂于水深火热的紧急任务!
Now, where's the train?
车在哪里?
Here it comes.
啊! 来了
What did Marty say to you? I asked you to talk to him.
马蒂对你说了什么? 我让你和他谈谈!
I did! I did! I don't understand. He said, "Let's go. "
我谈了! 我谈了! 我不明白! 他说:我们走!
I said, "Are you crazy? " He says, "I'm ten years old. "
我说:你疯了吗? 接着他说:我已经10岁了!
And he has black-and-white stripes, and so then we sang and...
然后是他有黑白条纹 再然后我们就一起唱歌
What you got to do is go straight back down West 42nd.
你要做的就是直走到西42街
It's on your left after Vanderbilt.
在你左手边范德大楼后面
If you hit the Chrysler Building, you've gone too far.
如果你到了克莱斯勒大楼 就是走过了
Thanks a lot, officer.
非常感谢 长官
Hey! Wait for the light.
嘿! 等着信号灯!
Freak.
怪人
- Did you say "zebra"? - That's right. A zebra.
- 你是说"斑马"吗? - 对 没错 斑马
Right in front of me.
就在我面前
- Can I shoot it? - Negative.
- 我能开枪吗? - 别开
Then I'm going to need some backup.
那我需要支援
- Aw! Knicks lost again. - What are you going to do.
- 噢! 尼克斯队又输了一场 - 那又怎么样?
Did that say "Grand Central Station" or "my aunt's constipation"?
广播说的是"中央车站"还是"我阿姨便秘"?
This is it.
就是这里了!
Grand Central Station.
中央车站!
It's grand and it's central.
很大而且在中央
Move aside. We have an emergency here. This is an emergency situation.
让一下 我们有紧急情况 这是紧急情况!
Hey, hey. Just chill out. It's not that big of an emergency.
嗨 嗨 冷静! 不是那么严重的紧急情况
Upstairs, downstairs.
我上 我下
How do you like that?
再试试这个滋味如何?
Lady! What is wrong with you?
女士 你怎么了?
Ow! Get a grip on yourselves, people.
管好你的人!
You're a bad kitty.
你这只坏家伙!
Dagnabbit! I missed the express.
该死 我错过了快车!
Looks like I'll have to take the Stamford local.
似乎只能坐去斯坦福的慢车了
I got him! I've got him!
我抓到他了! 我抓到他了!
He's got him!
他抓到他了!
He's got him! He's got him! He's got...
他抓到他了! 他抓到他了! 他抓
I got something for you!
我也有好东西给你!
I'm okay. I'm okay.
我没事 我没事
Whoa! What are you guys doing here?
哇! 你们来干吗?
- I am so glad we found you. - We were so worried about you.
- 哦 我们很高兴找到了你 - 我们很担心你!
Don't worry, I'm fine, I'm fine. Look at me. I'm fine.
别担心 我很好 我很好 你们看 我很好
You're fine? Oh, he's fine. Oh, great.
你很好? 哦 他很好! 哦 太好了
You hear that? Marty's fine. That's good to know.
嘿 你听见了 马蒂很好 这样就好
Because I was wondering...
因为我刚刚在想
How could you do this to us? I thought we were your friends!
你怎么能这么对我们 马蒂? 我以为我们是你的朋友!
What's the big deal? I was coming back.
这没什么大不了的! 我早上就回来了!
Don't ever do this again. Do you hear me?
以后不许了 听见没有?
- Do you hear him? - Guys, we're running out of time.
- 听见没有? - 伙计们 我们没时间了!
Oh, Melman, you broke their clock?
哦 梅尔曼 你弄坏了他们的钟?
... do this again! Don't you ever, ever do this again!
不许了! 以后再也再也不许了!
Come here.
用力啊
We've been ratted out, boys.
我们被包围了
Hold your fire!
别开枪
Cute and cuddly, boys. Cute and cuddly.
可爱讨喜点 小家伙们 扮可爱点
If you have any poo, fling it now.
如果你有什么招示 赶快使出来
It's the Man.
是人类
Good evening, officers.
晚上好 长官!
No. No. No. You don't talk now. Okay?
不 不 你别说话 好吗?
You're not good with the "putting words together
你不擅长言表
and their coming out good" thing. You keep it "shh. "
你闭嘴就好!
Hey! How you doing? You know what? Everything's cool.
嘿! 你们好吗? 这里一切都好
We just had a little situation here. Little internal situation.
只是出了点小状况 内部的小状况
My friend went a little crazy. Happens to everybody.
事实上我朋友有点疯过头了 每个人都会这样的
The city gets to us all. Went a little cuckoo in the head.
只是脑筋搭错了线
Don't be calling me cuckoo in the head.
嘿! 别说我搭错了线!
Just shush! I will handle this.
别说话! 我来解决!
Oh! I got him!
我踢到他了!
Go, go, go! Right here, please.
快快快! 这边
Would you give a guy a break?
你能不这样吗?
We'll take my little friend home and forget this ever happened. All right?
我们准备把我们的朋友带回去 忘记发生过的一切 好吗?
No harm, no foul, right?
没有伤害和子弹 好吗?
Hey, it's cool. It's me, Alex the lion. From the zoo.
哦 不 不 不 嘿 冷静! 是我 亚里克斯 动物园的狮子
What's the matter with them?
他怎么了?
I feel really, really weird.
哇哦! 我感觉好奇怪
I love you guys.
嘿! 我爱你们
I love you so much.
我非常爱你们
Last night's dramatic incident in Grand Central
昨晚在中央车站的事件
is an example of what animal rights wackos have been shouting for years:
是多年来呼吁动物权利的一个例子
Animals clearly don't belong in captivity.
动物很显然不该被囚禁
They are to be sent back to their natural habitat,
现在他们要被送回到自然的生活环境中
where they will live their lives in the freedom they desire.
在那里他们可以自由自在 地过他们渴望的生活
- Hey. Little help? - He's awake! He's awake!
- 嘿 帮帮忙 - 他醒了! 他醒了!
Do something!
快想办法!
Oh, man.
哦 天!
Oh, my head.
哦 我的头!
What the... ?
什么破 ?
Wait. Where? What?
哪里? 怎么了?
I'm in a box! Oh, no. No, no! Not the box.
我在箱子里! 噢不! 不不! 不要箱子!
Oh, no, they can't transfer me. Not me!
噢不 他们不能送我走! 不是我!
Oh, I can't breathe. I can't breathe.
我不能呼吸了 我不能呼吸了
Darkness creeping in.
黑暗袭来
I can't breathe. I can't breathe.
不能呼吸了 我不能呼吸!
Walls closing in around me.
墙向我缩进!
So alone. So alone.
好孤独 好孤独
- Alex! Alex, are you there? - Marty?
- 亚里克斯! 亚里克斯 你在那吗? - 马蒂?
- Yeah! Talk to me, buddy. - Oh, Marty! You're here!
- 对! 跟我说话! - 哦 马蒂! 你在这!
- What's going on? You okay? - This doesn't look good.
- 发生什么事了? 你还好吗? - 不太好 马蒂
- Alex, Marty, is that you? - Gloria!
- 亚里克斯 马蒂 是你们吗 - 格洛瑞尔!
- You're here too! - I am loving the sound of your voice.
- 你也在! - 我爱死了你的声音!
- What is going on? - We're all in crates.
- 发生什么事了? - 我们在箱子里
Oh, no!
哦 不!
- Sleeping just knocks me out. - Melman!
- 我睡得昏昏沉沉的 - 梅尔曼!
Is that Melman?
是梅尔曼吗?
- Are you okay? - Yeah. No, I'm fine.
- 你没事吧? - 我没事
I often doze off while I'm getting an MRl.
我做完核磁共振检查后总是会昏昏沉沉的
- You're not getting an MRl. - CAT scan?
- 你没有做核磁共振检查 - 切片扫描?
No CAT scan. It's a transfer. It's a zoo transfer.
不是切片扫描? 是转园! 转园!
Zoo transfer? ! Oh, no. No, no, I can't be transferred.
转园? ! 哦 不 不 不 我不要转园
I have an appointment with Dr. Goldberg at 5:00.
我和戈德堡医生5点有约
There are prescriptions that have to be filled.
我的药吃完了
No other zoo could afford my medical care.
没有别的动物园能给我如此的医疗照顾!
And I am not going HMO.
我哪也不去
Take it easy, Melman. It's going to be okay.
没事梅尔曼 一切都会好的
- We are going to be okizay. - No, we're not going to be okizay.
- 我们会没事的 - 不马蒂 我们不会没事
Now, because of you, we're ruined!
现在因为你我们都毁了!
Because of me? I fail to see how this is my fault.
因为我? 我倒想看看怎么是我的责任
- You're kidding, right, Marty? - You. You ticked off the people.
- 你开玩笑的 是不是马蒂? - "你! 你把我们都惹火了"?
You bit the hand, Marty. You bit the hand.
你恩将仇报 马蒂 你恩将仇报
"l don't know who I am. I got to go find myself in the wild. " Oh, please.
"我不知道我是谁 我不知道我是谁 我要在野外找到自我"
I did not ask you to come after me, did l?
嘿! 我没有让你们来找我 对吧?
He does have a point.
他说得对
- What? - I did say we should stay at the zoo, but you guys...
- 什么? - 我说过我们应该待在动物园里 但你们
Melman, just shut it.
梅尔曼 闭嘴!
You suggested this idea to him in the first place.
你第一个出的主意
- Leave Melman out of this. - Thank you, Gloria.
- 亚里克斯 别把梅尔曼扯进来 - 谢谢 格洛瑞尔
Besides, it's not my fault that we were transferred.
还有亚里克斯 我们被转园不是我的错!
Melman, shut it. Does anybody feel nauseous?
梅尔曼 闭嘴 你们谁觉得恶心?
- I feel nauseous. - Melman, you always feel nauseous.
- 我觉得 - 梅尔曼 你总是觉得恶心
Progress report.
进度报告
It's an older code, skipper. I can't make it out.
这是旧式编码 船长 我不认识
You, higher mammal.
你 高级哺乳动物
Can you read?
你识字吗?
No. Phil can read, though. Phil.
不认 但是菲尔认字 菲尔
Ship to Kenya.
运往肯尼亚
Wildlife preserve.
野生动物保护区
Africa!
非洲
Africa? That ain't going to fly. Rico.
非洲 那可不行 里科!
I was the star in the greatest city on Earth.
我曾是世上最伟大城市里的大明星!
- Guys, listen. - A king. Loved by my people.
- 伙计们 听着 - 被人热爱的国王!
- Let's be civil. - And you've ruined everything!
- 让我们文明一点 - 你毁了一切!
"Loved"?
"爱"?
If the people loved you, it's only because they didn't know the real you!
如果人们爱你 那只是因为他们不认识真正的你!
Don't make me come up there. I'll whoop both of y'all.
别让我上去 胖揍你们俩一顿!
I thought I knew the real you!
我以为我了解真正的你!
Your black-and-white stripes, they cancel each other out. You're nothing!
你个黑白条纹的 他们在你之后取消了一切权利!
Stop it, stop it, stop it!
停! 停! 停! 停!
You're not helping the situation.
嘿! 你们要有耐心
Status.
状态
It's no good. I don't know the codes.
情况不妙 我不知道密码!
Don't give me excuses. Give me results! Navigation.
不要借口! 给我结果! 导航!
All right. Let me think.
好吧 让我想想
And shut him up!
让他闭嘴!
- I did it! - Let's get this tin can turned around.
- 我成功了! - 让我们把船掉头!
Guys?
伙计们?
Oh, no.
哦 不
Gloria!
格洛瑞尔!
Melman!
梅尔曼!
Marty!
马蒂!
Alex!
亚里克斯!
Marty? !
马蒂? !
Alex!
亚里克斯!
Marty!
马蒂!
No, wait. Come back, Marty!
不! 等等! 回来 马蒂!
Don't go.
别走
Marty?
马蒂?
Melman?
梅尔曼?
Gloria?
格洛瑞尔?
Marty? !
马蒂? !
Melman? !
梅尔曼? !
Gloria? !
格洛瑞尔? !
Marty!
马蒂!
Melman! Gloria!
梅尔曼! 格洛瑞尔!
Hey, anyone! Hello!
嘿有人吗? 哈喽!
Marty, Melman, Gloria.
马蒂 梅尔曼 格洛瑞尔
Gloria, Melman, Marty. Marty, Gelman, Gloria. Marty, Melman.
格洛瑞尔 梅尔曼 马蒂 马蒂 吉尔曼 格洛瑞尔 马蒂 梅尔曼
Morty, Morty, Gelman. Regis. Kelly.
莫蒂 莫蒂 吉尔曼 丽贾斯 凯利
Matt, Katie, Al.
马特 凯特 艾尔
Get me out of this thing. Somebody. Hello?
让我出去 有人吗! 哈喽?
Get me out of this thing right now!
马上让我出去!
Hello? Somebody?
哈喽? 有人吗?
Melman!
梅尔曼!
Alex? Is that you?
亚里克斯? 是你吗?
Melman, I got you. Hang on! Hang on. I got you.
梅尔曼 我找到你了! 坚持 坚持 我找到你了
Melman! I got you, buddy.
梅尔曼! 我找到你了 伙计!
Wait a sec, Melman. Wait right there.
等会儿 梅尔曼 等着
- What are you doing? - I'm getting you out of the box.
- 亚里克斯 你在干吗? - 把你弄出来!
- Relax. - Alex?
- 放松 - 亚里克斯?
Giraffe, corner pocket!
长颈鹿 四分位!
Here goes nothing!
亚里克斯来啦!
- Wait, wait, wait, wait. - Hold still!
- 等等! 等等! 别! 等等! - 别动!
- Wait, Alex. - Hold still.
- 等等 亚里克斯 - 别动
- No, come on. - Here I come!
- 不! 别! - 我来啦!
Look! Look! Look! Look!
看! 看! 看! 看!
It's Gloria. It's Gloria!
是格洛瑞尔! 是格洛瑞尔!
Oh, hey, it is Gloria.
哦嘿 是格洛瑞尔
Oh, my...
哦 我的
Gloria!
格洛瑞尔!
Alrighty, boys, fun's over.
好了伙计们 娱乐结束
Gloria!
格洛瑞尔!
Alex!
亚里克斯!
- Marty? ! - Marty!
- 马蒂? ! - 马蒂!
Yeah! All right! That's right!
嘢! 对! 就这样!
Left! Left! Left. No, no, your left! Your left! Your left!
左边! 左边! 左边 不 不对 是你的左边! 你的左边! 你的左边!
Right here's good.
就在这儿下就好了
I don't have anything on me right now. I'll have to get you later.
我现在什么都没有 以后再给你们
To you too.
你也是
Marty!
马蒂!
Alex!
亚里克斯!
Marty!
马蒂!
Alex!
亚里克斯!
Marty!
马蒂!
Al!
艾尔!
Marty!
马蒂!
Alex?
亚里克斯?
Marty!
马蒂!
Oh, sugar, honey, ice tea.
哦 糖 蜂蜜 冰茶
Martin!
马蒂!
- Hold up! - I'm going to kill you!
- 等等! - 我要杀了你!
- Come here! Don't run away from me! - Calm down!
- 你给我过来! 不许再跑! - 冷静点!
If you keep running, I'm going to just kill you more!
如果你再跑 我就用更厉害的招示来对付你
Oh, look at us.
哦 看看我们
We're all here together. Safe and sound.
我们在一起 毫发无伤
Yeah, here we are.
对 我们在这
Where exactly is "here"?
"这"到底是什么地方?
San Diego.
圣地亚哥
San Diego?
圣地亚哥?
White sandy beaches,
白沙海岸
cleverly simulated natural environment, wide-open enclosures.
精致的模拟自然环境 宽广的场地
I'm telling you, this could be the San Diego Zoo.
我告诉你这可能是圣地亚哥动物园
Complete with fake rocks.
完全仿造的石头
Wow, that looks real.
哇! 看上去很真实
San Diego? What could be worse than San Diego?
圣地亚哥? 还有什么比圣地亚哥更糟的?
I don't know. This place is crackalacking!
我不知道 这个地方很棒 我喜欢!
Oh, I could hang here. I could hang here.
哦 我可以留在这 我可以留在这
- I'll kill you! - Take it easy!
- 我要杀了你 马蒂! - 放松! 放松!
- Strangle you! - Calm down.
- 然后勒死你! - 冷静
Then bury you, dig you up, clone you and kill your clones.
然后埋了你 再把你挖出来 然后克隆你! 再把所有克隆的你都杀了!
- 20-second timeout. - I'll never talk to you again.
- 20秒的暂停! - 我再也不理你了
Now, look. We're just going to find the people,
别闹了! 听着 我们得先找到人
get checked in and have this mess straightened out.
向他们报到 然后结束这出闹剧
Oh, great. This is just great. San Diego.
哦 好呀 这真是太好了 圣地亚哥
Now I'll have to compete with Shamu and his smug little grin.
我得去和杀人鲸竞争 那些得意地咧着嘴笑的家伙
I can't top that. Can't top it.
我比不过他们 我赢不了他们
I'm ruined! I'm done. I'm out of the business.
我完了! 我彻底完蛋了 我失业了
It's your fault, Marty! You've ruined me.
这都是你的错 马蒂! 你把我给毁了
Come on, Alex. Do you honestly think
嗨 亚里克斯 你好好想想
I intended all of this to happen?
现在这样全都是我的错吗?
You want me to say that I'm sorry? Is that what you want?
你是想我给你道歉吗? 这就是你想要的吗?
- Okay, I'm... - Shh!
- 那好 对不 - 嘘!
He just shushed me.
他嘘我
- Marty, look, you've got to be just a little bit more und... - Shh!
- 马蒂 你看 你应该多理解别人... - 嘘!
- Don't you shush me. - Do you hear that? Don't you hear that?
- 你是在嘘我吗? - 你们听到吗? 你们都没听到那声音吗?
- I hear it now. - Where there's music, there's people.
- 我现在听到了 - 有音乐的地方就有人类
- Go to the head honcho. - A sidewalk would be nice.
- 我们直接去找老板 - 要有人行道就好了
Yeah, what a dump.
是啊 这地方真差劲
They should call it the San Di-lame-o Zoo.
他们应该叫这里圣地残哥动物园
First they tell you, "We got this great open plan thing. Let animals run wild. "
首先他们告诉你:"我们有个超棒的开放计划 让所有动物都到野外去尽情狂奔"
Next thing, flowers in your hair, everybody's hugging everybody.
然后就有人扔花 大家相互拥抱
This place kind of grows on you. This way, guys! Come on!
这真是个令人喜欢的地方 伙计们 在这边! 快来!
What the... ?
这是什么鬼 ?
Oh, no!
哦 不!
Okay, let's make a good impression on the people.
好了 让我们给这些人留个不错的第一印象
Smiles, everyone. Let's get it together.
笑起来 然后一块儿出去
- Is that the best you can do? - Oh, I'm not smiling. It's gas.
- 梅尔曼 这就是你最灿烂的笑容吗? - 哦 我没笑 是想放屁
Well, great. Let's make gas look good.
哦 好吧 让我们放屁也放得漂亮
- Wow! - It's not people. It's animals.
- 哇! - 这不是人类 还是动物
California animals. Dude.
加洲的动物
This is like a Puffy party.
这就象是帕妃的派对
I like to move it, move it I like to move it, move it
我喜欢跳舞 跳舞 我喜欢跳舞 跳舞
- Ya like to - Move it
- 你喜欢 - 跳舞
I like to move it, move it I like to move it, move it
我喜欢跳舞 跳舞 我喜欢跳舞 跳舞
I like to move it, move it
我喜欢跳舞 跳舞
- Ya like to - Move it
- 你喜欢 - 跳舞
I like to move it, move it You like to move it, move it
我喜欢跳舞 跳舞 你喜欢跳舞 跳舞
She like to move it, move it
她喜欢跳舞 跳舞
- He like to - Move it
- 他喜欢 - 跳舞
All girls all over the world
世上所有的女孩
Original King Julien 'pon yer case, man
我是国王朱利安
I love how all the girls that love to move their body
我爱所有爱跳舞的女孩
When ya move your body, ya do
如果你想跳舞
Move it nice and sweet and sassy, all right
那就漂亮地舞 尽情地舞 热情地舞 舞起来
What kind of zoo is this?
这是个什么样的动物园啊?
I just saw 26 blatant health code violations.
我刚刚看到有26条健康准则被违反
I'm loving San Diego. This place is off the chizain.
我爱圣地亚哥 这地方实在太炫了
Twenty-seven.
27条
Woman, physically fit, physically fit
女人 苗条 苗条
Physically, physically, physically fit Physically fit, Physically fit
苗条 苗条 苗条 苗条 苗条
We should've brought chips and dip.
我们应该带着薯片来
Wait.
等等
Where's Alex? What happened to him? He was right behind us. Wasn't he?
亚里克斯在哪里? 他怎么了? 他刚刚就在我们后面的 不是吗?
I don't know where he's at, but he's missing one heck of a party.
我不知道他去哪里了 反正他错过了派对
The fossa!
伏狼来了!
The fossa are attacking! Run for your lives!
伏狼入侵啦! 快逃命啊!
- Fossa hungry. - Fossa eat.
- 伏狼饿了 - 伏狼有东西吃了
I hate spiderwebs.
我讨厌蜘蛛网
Yeah, thanks a lot, guys.
哦 伙计们 谢谢了
Thanks for waiting up. Really appreciate it.
谢谢你们等我 实在很感谢
Hey, hi. We just got in from New York, and we're looking for a supervisor.
嗨 你们好 我们刚从纽约过来 我们想见负责人
Because we've been sitting on that beach back there for hours,
因为我们已经在沙滩上坐了几个小时了
and nobody's even bothered to show up.
还没有任何人来接待我们
I don't know how things are normally run around here,
我不知道这里的规矩是什么
but there's been some sort of major screwup, which is cool.
不过有些事情显然没安排好
So if you could point us towards the administrative offices, we'll...
所以如果你们可以告诉我们管理人员的办公室在哪里 那我们就
Well, howdy-do.
很高兴认识你
Spider! Spider! Spider on my back!
哇! 蜘蛛! 蜘蛛! 我背上有蜘蛛!
Maurice, did you see that?
莫里斯 你看到了吗?
He scared the fossa away.
他把伏狼吓跑了
Come on, Gloria. Get it.
快 格洛瑞尔 打他
Get it! Get it! Get it!
打他! 打他! 打他!
- That's it! Smack it! - Get it, get it!
- 他在这! 快打他! - 快打 打!
Whip it! Whip it good! Where'd it go?
扁他! 扁他! 他去哪儿了?
King Julien, what are they? What are they? !
朱利安 国王陛下 他们是什么东西? 他们是什么啊? !
They are aliens. Savage aliens from the savage future.
他们是外星人 从未开化的未来来的野蛮外星人
They've come to kill us. And take our women. And our precious metals.
他们来屠杀我们 掠走我们的妇女 抢夺我们珍贵的金属
Get up, Mort. Do not be near the king's feet, okay?
起来 小姑娘 离国王的脚远点 明白吗?
We're hiding. Be quiet, everyone. Including me.
嘘 我们在躲难 所有的人 连我在内 都要保持安静
Who's making that noise?
谁发出声音了?
Oh, it's me again.
哦 又是我
There it is! Get it! Come on, Gloria!
他在这儿! 揍他! 快 格洛瑞尔!
- Enough! Enough with the stick. - I think she got it.
- 够了! 别再用棍子打了 - 我想她打着了
Is it still on me? I hate spiders.
他还在我身上吗? 我讨厌蜘蛛
It's okay. It's gone.
没事了 没有了
They are savages.
他们是野人
Tonight we die.
我们活不过今晚了
The feet. I told you... I told you to... I told every...
我的脚! 我告诉过你 我说过 我告诉过每个
Didn't I tell him about the feet?
我没告诉过他离我的脚远点吗?
He did tell you about the feet.
他确实告诉过你
- Wait. I have a plan. - Really?
- 等等 我有个计划 - 真的?
I have devised a cunning test
我想出了一个绝妙的主意
to see whether these are savage killers.
试试看他们是不是凶残的杀手
Hi there.
嘿 你好
You let me handle it. Alex handles it. Marty does nothing.
让我来处理 亚里克斯处理事情 马蒂什么也别管
Hi there.
嘿 你好
Oh, jeez. Sorry.
哦 天啊 对不起
- Oh, Alex, what'd you do? - Stop. Stop. It's okay. It's okay.
- 哦 亚里克斯 你都干了些什么? - 别哭 别哭 没事的 没事的
I'm just a silly... Just a silly lion. Oh, jeez!
我只是头苯苯的 只是头笨笨的狮子 哦 天哪!
- Aw, Alex! - Oh, you poor little baby.
- 哦 亚里克斯! - 哦 可怜的小家伙
Did that big mean lion scare you?
是不是这讨厌的大狮子吓到你了?
He did? He's a big, bad old puddy tat, isn't he?
吓着你了么? 他是个大大的坏小孩 对吧?
Come on. Mama'll hold you. Aww, look at you.
过来 妈妈抱抱 哦 看看你
They are so cute from a reasonable distance.
从某种意义上他们非常可爱
Aren't you the sweetest little thing. I just want to dunk him in my coffee.
你真是个小可爱 我真想把它加进我的咖啡里
They're just a bunch of pansies.
他们只是一群小白脸吧
I don't know.
我不知道
There's something about that one with the crazy hairdo
我觉得那个梳着爆炸头的
that I find suspicious.
还是很可疑
Nonsense, Maurice.
胡说 莫里斯!
Come on, everybody. Let's go and meet the pansies!
来吧 大家! 我们去见见小白脸们
Presenting your royal highness, our illustrious King Julien Xlll,
尊敬的陛下 杰出的国王朱利安13世
self-proclaimed lord of the lemurs, et cetera. Hooray, everybody.
狐猴之王 等等 等等 自己宣布驾到 欢呼万岁
He's got style.
他真有形
What is he, like, king of the guinea pigs?
他是什么呀 新西兰几维猪之王?
I think it's a squirrel.
我觉得是松鼠
Welcome, giant pansies.
欢迎你们 大个子小白脸!
Please feel free to bask in my glow.
在我的领域尽情享受阳光吧
- Definitely a squirrel. - Yep. Squirrel.
- 就是松鼠 - 对 是松鼠
We thank you with enormous gratitude for chasing away the fossa.
对于你们赶走伏狼 我以最诚挚的谢意
- The "whossa"? - The fossa.
- 狐狼? - 伏狼
They annoy us by trespassing, interrupting our parties
他们总是侵入我们的领地 破坏我们的晚会
- and ripping our limbs off. - Good.
- 打断我们的四肢 - 是的 听起来不错
We're just trying to find out where the people are, so...
听着 我们只是 我们只是在找哪里有人
What big teeth you have. Man!
哦 天! 你的牙齿好大! 人类!
Shame on you, Maurice. Can you not see that you have insulted the freak?
真为你感到羞愧 莫里斯! 你没发现你在侮辱这些怪物吗?
You must tell me, who the heck are you?
你们必须告诉我 你们到底是谁?
I'm Alex. The Alex. And this is Gloria, Marty and Melman.
我是亚里克斯 那个亚里克斯 这是格洛瑞尔 马蒂和梅尔曼
And just where are you giants from?
你们这些巨人是从哪里来的?
We're from New York and...
我们从纽约来 我们…
All hail the New York giants!
为纽约来的巨人们欢呼!
New York giants!
纽约巨人!
Is this some sort of inbreeding program?
我们在做什么? 某种近亲繁殖项目?
I say we just got to ask these bozos where the people are.
我觉得我们只要问问这些傻瓜人类在哪里就可以了
Excuse me. We bozos have the people, of course.
对不起 我们这些傻瓜也有人类
Hey, the bozos have the people.
嘿 这些傻瓜有人类!
Oh, well, great. Good. Phew.
哦 好呀 好
They're up there.
他们在那上面
Don't you love the people? Not a very lively bunch, though.
你们喜欢人类吗? 尽管不是太活跃的一群
Wow.
哇哦
So do you have any live people?
那你们有没有活着的人类呢?
No. Only dead ones.
没有 只有死人
I mean, if we had a lot of live people here,
我的意思是 如果我们这里有很多活人
it wouldn't be called the wild, would it?
这里不会叫作"野生世界"了 对吧?
The wild?
野生世界?
Whoa. Hold up there a second, fuzzbucket.
等一等
You mean, like,
你是说
the "live in a mud hut, wipe yourself with a leaf" type wild?
住在泥浆小屋里? 用野生树叶清理你自己?
- Who wipes? - Oy vey.
- 谁清理? - 天哪
- Oy vey! - Oy vey, everybody!
- 天哪! - 大家一起!
Oy vey!
天哪!
Could you excuse me for a moment?
能允许我离开一会儿吗?
Get me out of here! We got to get out of here!
让我离开这里! 我们得离开这里!
- Help! - What are you doing? !
- 救命! - 你在做什么?
I'm swimming back to New York.
我要游回纽约去!
I know my chances are slim, but I have to try!
我知道我不会游泳! 不过我必须得试试!
- You can't swim! - I said my chances are slim!
- 你不会游泳! - 我说过我没有机会了!
Nature! It's all over me! Get it off! I can't see! I can't see!
大自然! 全在我身上了! 把它弄下来! 我看不见了! 我看不见了!
I can see!
我能看见!
Look. There's obviously just been a little mistake.
好吧 听着 很显然 这其中有点小小的误会
The people didn't dump us here on purpose.
人类并不是故意把我们丢在这里的
As soon as they realize what happened, they'll come looking for us, right?
他们一旦发现发生了什么 他们就会回来找我们 对吧?
Yeah, right.
是 对的
I don't know the words But we're born free
我不知道怎么用言语形容 可我们生来就是自由的
You know something? I bet they're already on their way.
你知道吗? 我敢说他们已经在找我们的路上了
Well, boys, it's going to be ice-cold sushi for breakfast.
好了 兄弟们 我们的早餐 将是冰冻寿司
Rico.
里科
Well, since I'm doomed to die on this forsaken island,
因为我命中注定在这座孤岛上死去
I, Melman Mankiewicz,
我 梅尔曼 门科维兹
being of sound mind and unsound body,
在身体健康 神志清醒的状态下
have divided my estate equally among the three of you.
将我的财产平均分给你们三个人
Sorry, Alex.
哦 对不起 亚里克斯
Hey! A latrine. Nice work, Melman. Outdoor plumbing.
嘿! 一个厕所 做得不错 梅尔曼 还是户外抽水的
No, it's not a latrine.
不 这不是厕所
It's a grave. You sent Melman to his grave. Are you happy?
是坟墓 你把梅尔曼送进了坟墓 你高兴了?
Aw, come on.
哦 别这样
This isn't the end. This is a whole new beginning.
这不是世界末日 这是一个崭新的开始!
This could be the best that's happened.
这对我们来说再好不过
No. No. No. No.
不是不是不是不是!
No. No. No. No. No. No. This is not the best thing that's happened to us.
不是不是不是不是不是不是! 这对我们来说一点都不好
You abused the power of the birthday wish and brought bad luck on all of us.
你的生日愿望被诅咒了 给我们都带来了霉运
Why'd you tell your wish? You're not supposed to.
你为什么要告诉我们你的愿望? 你不应该那样做!
I didn't want to tell you. Remember?
等等 我不想告诉你们的 还记得吗?
- You guys made me tell you. - Oh, okay.
- 是你们让我说出来的 - 哦
Besides, this isn't bad luck. This is good luck.
另外 这不是霉运 这是好运
Look around. There's no fences, no schedules.
看看我们周围吧 没有围栏 没有作息时间
This place is beautiful. Baby, we were born...
多美的地方啊 我们生来就
Okay. Okay. I've had enough of this.
好了 我要阻止这一切了
This is your side of the island, and this is our side of the island.
这边你的岛屿活动范围 这边是我们的岛屿活动范围
That is the bad side, where you can prance and skip
在坏的那边你可以像一只神奇木马一样又蹦又跳
Iike a magical pixie horse and do whatever the heck you want.
天天做你想做的该死的那些事情而这边
This is the good side for those who love New York and care about going home.
这边是好的一部分 给我们这些热爱纽约想要回家的人们
- Come on. - No, no. Back! Back!
- 别这样 - 不 不! 后退 后退!
You know what? This isn't good.
你知道吗 这不太好
Okay! You all have your side, and I'll have mine.
好了! 你们呆在你那边吧 我也呆在我自己这边
And if you need me, I'll be over here,
如果你们需要我 我就过去
on the fun side of the island, having a good old time.
在这边快乐的土地上 享受昔日好风光
This is the fun side,
这是快乐的土地! 这是快乐的土地!
where we'll have a great time surviving until we go home.
我们都会活下去并且过得很好 直到我们回到家!
- A yabbadabbado old time! - This side's the best.
- 美好的旧时光! - 我喜欢这片土地! 这片土地最好了!
That side stinks! You're on the Jersey side of this cesspool!
那边臭死了! 你就在粪池的旁边
- Wilma! - Now what do we do?
- 威尔玛! - 那我们现在怎么办呢?
Don't worry. I have a plan to get us rescued.
别担心梅尔曼 我有自救的计划了
Can't wait to see the look on Marty's face when he sees this.
真想看看马蒂看到这个以后他的表情
Just look at him. He's helpless without us.
看看他吧 没有我们 他是那么无助
Shut up, Spalding.
住嘴 椰子头
I've been standing here for hours, man.
伙计们 我在这里站了几个小时了
How long do I have to pose like this?
我还像这样摆姿势多久?
She is finito.
她叫菲尼特!
I defy any rescue boat within a million miles
我要让所有一百万公里以内的救援队伍
to miss this baby.
想念这个宝贝
When the moment is right, we will ignite the beacon of liberty
当时机来临时 我们要点燃这个 自由之灯塔
and be rescued from this awful nightmare!
把我们从噩梦中救醒
What do you think? Pretty cool, huh?
你们觉得怎么样? 很酷吧 哈?
- How's the liberty fire going, Melman? - Great. Idiot.
- 自由之火怎么样了 梅尔曼? - 很好! 白痴
I heard that.
我听见了
Why can't we just borrow some of Marty's fire?
我们为什么不借用一下马蒂的火?
That's wild fire. We're not using wild fire on Lady Liberty.
那是野生之火! 我们在自由女神身上不用野生之火
- Now, rub, Melman. - I've been doing...
- 快点摩擦 梅尔曼! - 我一直在做
I can't. I can't. I can't do it. I ju... I can't do it!
我弄不出来 我弄不出来 我弄不出来 我就是 弄不出来!
Fire.
火
着火了
Fire! Fire!
着火了! 着火了!
Oh, my
噢天
Fire!
着火了!
Not yet! No, no! No!
不! 不要!
Fire!
着火了!
Melman, hold still!
梅尔曼 拿稳了!
Jump! Alex, jump!
跳下来! 亚里克斯 跳下来!
Don't worry, cats always land on their...
别担心 狮子总能用
Face? Man, what kind of cat are you?
脸落地 你是什么狮子啊?
You maniac!
你这个疯子!
You burned it up!
你把它烧掉了
Darn you!
该死!
Darn you all to heck!
真该死!
Can we go to the fun side now?
我们现在能到快乐的一边去了吗?
Everybody, calm down. Come on. Into your chairs.
大家静一静! 到这个洞里来吧
Everybody, calm down. Let go of his tail.
大家静一静 别踩他尾巴
Separate those two, would you, please?
请把他俩分开 好吗?
You here, you there. Everyone...
你到这边来 你到那边去
Calm down, people, okay?
冷静下来 好吗?
Now, presenting your royal highness, the illustrious blah, blah, blah.
欢呼尊贵的什么什么
You know, et cetera, et cetera. Hooray. Let's go.
什么什么陛下 驾到
Now, everybody,
各位!
we all have great curiosity about our guests, the New York giants.
我们对我们的客人“纽约巨人” 都充满了好奇
- Yes, Willie? - I like them.
- 是的 维利 - 我喜欢他们
I like them. I liked them first. Before I even met them I liked them.
我喜欢他们 我喜欢他们 我甚至在第一次见到他们之前就喜欢上他们了
I liked them right away. You hate them compared to how much I like them.
是的是的 我简直无法说出我有多喜欢他们
Oh, shut up. You're so annoying!
哦 闭嘴! 你知道你有多烦吗?
Now, for as long as we can remember,
听着! 我们还应该记得
we have been attacked and eaten by the dreaded fossa.
我们被讨厌的伏狼绑架并吃掉
The fossa! The fossa are attacking!
伏狼! 伏狼来了!
It's a cookbook! It's a cookbook!
这是本食谱! 是本食谱!
Please. Maurice.
请 请 莫里斯
Quiet!
嘘! 安静!
Come on, y'all. They're not attacking us this very instant.
你们别这样 非常时期他们不会攻击我们的
So my genius plan is this:
我的天才计划是这样的
We will make the New York giants
我们要和纽约巨人做朋友
our friends and keep them close.
和他们保持亲近
Then, with Mr. Alex protecting us,
然后有了亚里克斯先生保护我们
we will be safe and never have to worry
我们会很安全 我们就永远不必担心
about the dreaded fossa ever again.
可恶的伏狼了 永不
I thought of that. I thought of that. Yes. Me. I did.
我想到的! 我想到的! 是的! 我想到的!
Hold on, everybody. Hold on. I'm just thinking now.
等等 大家等等 我刚刚在想
I mean, does anyone wonder why the fossa
我的意思大家觉得为什么伏狼
were so scared of Mr. Alex?
这么害怕亚里克斯先生呢?
I mean, maybe we should be scared too.
我的意思是我们也许也该害怕的
What if Mr. Alex is even worse than the fossa?
要是亚里克斯先生比伏狼还可怕怎么办?
I tell you, that dude just gives me the heebiedabajeebies.
我告诉你们 那家伙让我害怕
Maurice, you did not raise your hand.
莫里斯 你没有举手
Therefore, your heinous comment will be stricken from the record.
所以你的发言将被磨掉
Does anyone else have the heebie-jeebies?
还有其他人觉得害怕的吗?
No? Good. So shut up.
没有! 好的! 那别说话了!
When the New York giants wake up,
当纽约巨人醒来的时候
we will make sure that they wake up in paradise.
我们要确保他们身在天堂之中
Now, who would like a cookie?
现在谁想要饼干?
Yo, Al. Melman and Gloria are over there having a good time.
亚里克斯 梅尔曼和格洛瑞尔在那边玩呢
There's room on the fun side for one more.
再加你一个就跟好玩了
No, thanks.
不 谢谢
Look, I've been thinking. Maybe if you gave this place a chance,
听着 我在想 也许你应该给这个地方一个机会
I don't know, you might even enjoy yourself.
你也许能过得很愉快
Marty, I'm tired. I'm hungry.
马蒂 我累了 我饿了
I just want to go home.
我只想回家
Could you just give it a chance? Think about it.
你能给它一个机会吗? 想想看吧
It really isn't the fun side without you.
没有你真的不好玩
I know. And then...
我知道 然后
- It's him. - Who is it?
- 是他! - 谁呀?
It's the pizza man. Who the heck do you think it is?
是送披萨的 你觉得会是谁呢?
Yes? Can I help you?
是? 我能为你效劳么?
Can I come to the fun side?
我能到这边快乐的土地来么?
Beg your pardon?
对不起 没听清楚
You know, I've been kind of a jerk.
我是挺有点过分 马蒂
But I've been thinking about what you said, and I'm sorry.
我一直在想你说的…对不起
Welcome to Casa del Wild. Take a load off.
欢迎来到我们的城堡! 卸下负担!
Hey, hey, wipe your feet.
嘿 嘿 擦一下你的脚再进来!
- Alex! - Mi casa is su casa.
- 亚里克斯! - 我的城堡就是你的城堡
Very impressive.
太棒了
Hey, have a drink. It's on the house.
嘿 来喝一杯 我请客!
This is seawater.
这是海水!
Oh, you don't swallow it. It's just temporary till the plumbing's done.
哦 你别吞下去! 计划实施以前这只是暂时的
Hey, y'all look hungry.
嘿 你很饿了吧
How would you like some of nature's goodness?
来点大自然的恩赐怎么样?
You have food?
你有吃的?
The Fun Side Special, coming up.
乐土的特别推荐 这就来!
Seaweed on a stick.
串串海草!
Seaweed?
海草? !
On a stick. Don't love it till you try it.
串串! 你尝过后就会喜欢的
That's unbelievable.
好吃得难以想象
- So good. - Well, thanks.
- 太棒了 - 嗯 谢谢!
It does kind of hit the spot, doesn't it?
非常养胃吧 对吧?
Well, maybe it could use a little lemon.
也许我还可以加点柠檬
No, it's great. It's really great. Doesn't get any better than this.
不 这已经很好了 很好了 还有比这个更好的么?
Oh, but it does.
哦 还真有
Check this out.
看看这个
Wow. Would you look at that.
哇! 快看啊
It's like billions and billions of helicopters.
像是许许多多的直升飞机
It's a shooting star. Make a wish. Quick!
是流星! 快许个愿! 快!
Ooh! How about a thick, juicy steak?
喔 来块又大又多汁的牛排?
You know what, Alex?
知道么亚里克斯!
I promise you I'm going to find you a steak tomorrow if it kills me.
我保证明天给你一大块牛排 撑死你
Thanks, Marty.
谢谢 马蒂
It is getting late. I guess I'm going to...
天色已晚 我想我要…
I think I'm going to hit the sack too.
我想我也要睡觉了
Sweet dreams, everyone.
大家美梦哟
Alex.
亚里克斯
What are you doing?
你在做什么?
Twenty-seven, 28, 29. Thirty black and only 29 white.
27 28 29 30条黑的 只有29条白的
Looks like you're black with white stripes after all.
似乎你的底色是黑色 再加上白色条纹
Dilemma solved. Good night.
问题解决了 各位晚安
You see, Maurice, Mr. Alex was grooming his friend.
你瞧 莫里斯 亚里克斯在给他的朋友化妆呢
He is clearly a tender, loving thing.
他是多么可爱温柔的小东西啊
How can you have the heebie-jeebies for Mr. Alex?
你怎么能觉得他很吓人呢?
Look at him. He's so cute and plushy.
看看他 他是那么可爱 那么帅气
I don't think he was grooming him.
我不觉得他是在给他化妆 朱利安
Look more like he was tasting him to me.
我倒是觉得像是在舔它
Suit yourself, no matter. I don't care.
随便你怎么说 不管怎么样 我不在乎
Soon we will put my excellent plan to action.
很快我的计划就要实现了
All we have to do is wait
我们要做的就是
until they are deep in their sleep.
等他们睡熟
How long is this going to take? !
还有多久?
Well, this sucks!
这 太讨厌了
Wake up, Mr. Alex.
醒醒 亚里克斯先生
Rise and shining.
太阳照着屁股了
Wakey-waking, Mr. Alex!
醒醒 醒醒 亚里克斯先生
Wake up! Alex!
醒醒 亚里克斯!
You suck your thumb?
你在吮手指头
Where are we? What the heck is going on?
我们在哪里? 到底发生什么事了?
Where's the beach? Take it easy.
沙滩到哪里去了? 别紧张
- Who built a forest? - Don't be alarmed, giant freaks.
- 谁建的森林? - 别害怕 大怪物
While you were asleep,
趁你们睡觉的时候
we simply took you to our little corner of heaven.
我们把你们带到了天堂的一角
Welcome to Madagascar.
欢迎来到马达加斯加!
- Mada-who-ah? - What?
- 马达瓦? - 什么?
No, not whooha. Ascar.
不 不是瓦 是加斯加
Marty. It's...
马蒂 这是…
Just like my mural back at the zoo.
就像是我的草地 好像回到了动物园
Oh, no, fella, that is the real deal right there.
不是的 伙计 那可是真家伙
Look at that, that's not a bad view.
看哪 我觉得景色还不错
That's the thing that you were always looking at, but it's actually there.
我的意思是那是你总能看到的东西 但是它就真真实实的就在眼前
- That's the real version of... - How about once around the park?
- 就像是真的版本 - 来赛跑怎么样?
Let's get our blood pumping, lungs breathing this fresh air.
让我们热血沸腾起来 让我们的肺吸入这么清新的空气
Who's with me? !
谁跟我一起? !
Naw. I don't think I could... You're it!
哦 不 我觉得我不行 你输了!
Hey! Want to play around?
嘿! 想来玩吗?
Got you there!
抓到你了!
Come here!
过来!
You're it.
你输了
Hey, stop that! Hey, you're crazy!
嘿 停下! 嘿 你疯了!
Okay, Marty, I'm it.
好吧 马蒂 我输了
I'm it. I'm it. You win.
我输了 你赢了
Come on, Alex, get in the groove.
来吧 亚里克斯 最佳状态
I haven't eaten in two days.
我两天没吃饭了
My blood sugar's real low. I just don't have the energy.
我的血糖非常低 我觉得我没有精力了
I don't think that's your problem.
我觉得那不是问题
First of all, that's not how you run in the wild.
首先 你在野生环境里不是这么跑步的
Let's go. Put the rubber to the road!
来吧 伙计! 把你的肉垫动起来
You just have to let out that inner lion.
你只需要让你真实的那个狮子爆发出来
- Now, who's the cat? - Marty, I really don't...
- 现在 谁才是狮子? - 马蒂 我真的不
You are, that's who. Come on! Here we go!
你行的! 那是谁呀! 来吧 我们走
That's it. Let's build up some steam! You the cat.
就是这样! 我们来出出汗 你是狮子
- Who's the cat? - You the cat.
- 谁是狮子? - 你是狮子
Who's the cat? Who's the cat? Who's the cat? Who's the cat?
谁是狮子? 谁是狮子? 谁是狮子? 谁是狮子?
I'm the cat!
我是狮子
Surprise!
惊喜!
You're it. You're it!
你输了! 你输了!
Can't juke the cat. Cat's too quick.
你抓不到 狮子跑得太快了
I feel like a mile-high pastrami on rye on the fly from the deli in the sky!
我觉得我在飞翔!
- Let's go wild! - Now you're talking!
- 我们去野外吧! - 你说的!
Man! I feel different.
伙计们 我感觉太棒了!
Noogie, noogie, noogie. Noogie, noogie, noogie!
哈哈哈哈!
Kind of charged up or something.
真是享受
- Like you said, baby, it's... - Crackalacking.
- 就像你说的 宝贝 - 这地方真棒
- Ain't that right, Melman? - Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah.
- 对吧 梅尔曼? - 哦 是的! 是的!
I'm in heaven.
我简直就在天堂里了
You see, Maurice, Alex is now our friend and the fossas are nowhere to be seen.
看到了 莫里斯 亚里克斯现在是我们的朋友了 再也看不到伏狼了
It could be said that my plan is working
可以说我的计划
in a very good working kind of way.
进行顺利
Alex. You got to try some of this.
亚里克斯 你应该试试这些
I feel good. Feel like a king again.
我感觉很好 我又觉得自己是国王了!
King?
国王?
You should see his act.
是的! 你应该看看他的表演!
Come on, Alex, why don't you show him some of your act.
来吧 亚里克斯 给他们看看你的表演
Oh. No, I really don't think I could... Okay.
不 我真的不想 好吧
Ladies and gentlemen. Primates of all ages.
女士们先生们 各位老人小孩
The wild proudly presents:
野生环境荣誉出品:
The king.
国王
Alex the lion!
狮子王亚里克斯
E flat, fellas.
伙计们 降E调
Yeah! The king is in the house!
耶! 国王来了!
See, if he is the king, then where is his crown? I've got a crown.
如果他是国王 它的王冠在那里? 我有王冠!
Got a very nice one. And it's here on my head.
有个非常好的! 就在我头上的!
Look at it. Have I got it on?
看看 我戴了吧?
Do the roar, man. Do the roar.
吼叫 兄弟 吼叫!
Wow. I've never heard that one before.
哇! 我以前从来没听过
Yeah! Go wild, man! Come on!
来个野性点的 来吧
Break out the wave!
来个人浪!
Excuse me.
对不起
You're biting my butt.
你在咬我的屁股
- No, I'm not. - Yes, you are.
- 不 我没有 - 是的 你咬了
- What did you do? - You just bit me!
- 亚里克斯 你做了什么? - 他咬了我的屁股
No. I didn't. Did l?
不 我没咬 我有咬吗?
You kind of did.
好象是有的
What the heck is wrong with you?
你发什么神经病啊?
Why'd you bite me?
你咬我干什么?
- Man, it's because you are his dinner. - What? !
- 伙计 因为你是他的晚餐 - 什么?
- Excuse me? - That's dumb.
- 你说什么? - 他在胡说八道
Come, come, Maurice. What is a simple bite on the buttocks among friends?
嘿 莫里斯 朋友间随便咬一口没什么的
Here, give me a nibble.
你 你也来咬我一口
The party is over, Julien. Your brilliant plan has failed.
派对结束了 朱利安 你的伟大计划完蛋了
What are you talking about?
你在说什么?
Your friend here is what we call
你的朋友就是我们所说的
a deluxe-model hunting and eating machine.
豪华型猎杀机器
And he eats steak...
他是吃肉的
... which is you.
也就是吃你
- Get out of here. - Okey-dokey, Maurice, I admit it.
- 胡说八道 - 好了 好了 莫里斯 我承认
The plan failed.
我的计划失败了
All is lost! We're all doomed.
全完了 我们注定要完蛋了
The fossas will come back and gobble us with their mouths because...
那些伏狼又会回来 把我们吃掉
... we are all steak.
因为我们都是肉类
I'm steak! Me, me, me!
我也是肉类 我是! 我是! 我是!
Mr. Alex cannot stay here.
亚里克斯先生不可以再留在这里
He belongs with his own kind on the fossa side of the island.
他得到岛的另外那边去 和他自己的同类伏狼在一起
By the power vested in me,
我以神赋予我的权力
by the law of the jungle, blah, blah, blah, blah...
按照森林法则等等等等法规宣布
Be gone!
马上离开!
What? Come on, do I look like a steak to you?
什么? 别乱说 你看着象块牛排吗?
Yeah!
对!
See, I told you I don't look like a... Wait. What you say?
看到了吗? 我就说我不会象 等等 你说什么?
Oh, yeah!
哦 非常象!
- He's going savage. - Run for your lives.
- 他开始变得凶残了 - 快去逃命
Marty, run!
马蒂 快逃!
A bull's eye. Excellent shot, Maurice.
正中靶心 打得好 莫里斯
Thank you.
谢谢
Marty?
马蒂?
I'm so sorry, Marty.
我真抱歉 马蒂
What is wrong with me?
我怎么了?
Ow.
嗷!
Oh, no.
哦 不
What have I done?
我都做了些什么啊?
It's true. I'm a monster.
这是真的 我是个魔鬼
I got to get out of here.
我得离开这里
What have I done? This is a nightmare.
我都做了些什么啊? 这真是个恶梦
And it's all my fault.
这都是我的错
Now, because of me, we've lost Alex.
就是因为我 我们失去了亚里克斯
Well, what are we going to do?
我们可以做些什么呢?
We'll find a way to help him. That's what we'll do.
我们可以想办法帮助他 这就是我们要做的
Okay.
好吧
- Come on, we are New Yorkers, right? - Yeah!
- 振作起来 我们是纽约人 对吗? - 对
- We're tough. We're gritty. - Yeah!
- 我们顽强不屈 我们坚韧不拔 - 没错!
- We're adaptable! - Yeah!
- 我们无所不能! - 就是!
And we are not going to lay down like a bunch of Melmans.
而且我们勇往直前 不会象那些长颈鹿一样被击倒
No, we're not.
不 我们绝不
Oh. Gloria.
哦 格洛瑞尔
That was not me, okay? That was the boat.
那不是我 知道吗? 是船的声音
- The boat! - The boat?
- 船! - 船?
The boat's come back for us! Come on, guys, we got to flag it down.
船回来接我们了! 快 伙计们 快去给他们发信号
There it is!
在那儿!
- Hey, over here! - Over here!
- 嘿 在这里! - 这边!
Over here! Yo!
这边啊!
Melman, give me a lift. Hurry up! Lift me up!
梅尔曼 把我顶起来 快! 把我顶起来!
Help! Help! Help!
救命啊! 救命啊! 救命啊!
- Oh, my neck. My neck. You guys. - Over here!
- 哦 我的脖子 我的脖子 你们这些家伙 - 这边!
- Melman! Steady. This way! - You have no idea how much this hurts.
- 梅尔曼! 别动 这边! - 你们不知道这样我有多疼
Hey, boat! We're over here!
嘿! 我们在这边啊!
Look! It's turning! It's coming back! It's coming back!
快看! 它在调头! 它正在往回开! 它开回来了!
Come on! Come on, baby!
过来! 快过来!
Yes! You guys.
真棒! 伙计
You flag down that boat. I'll get Alex.
你们把船拦下来 我去叫亚里克斯
Whoa! Hold on there.
哇! 别去
You cannot go back there by yourself.
你一个人去了就回不来了
Aw, come on. I know Alex.
别这么说 我了解亚里克斯
He hears we're rescued, he'll snap right out of it.
他一听说我们得救了 他就会振作起来了
The people are coming. They can help us.
人们马上就要来了 他们可以帮我们
Melman's right. The people will know what to do.
梅尔曼说得对 人类知道应该怎么做
Now, we got to flag down that boat.
我们现在先把船拦下来
Now, this is more like it.
这才是个象样的地方
You? ! Oh, ma... Where are the people?
是你们? ! 哦 天 那人在哪里?
We killed them and ate their livers.
我们把他们杀了 吃了他们的肝
Got you, didn't l?
骗到你了 不是吗?
Just kidding, doll, the people are fine.
和你开玩笑啦 宝贝儿 他们没事
They're on a slow lifeboat to China.
他们正搭救生艇慢慢摇去中国
Hey, I know you two.
嘿 我认识你们俩的
Where's that psychotic lion and our monochromatic friend?
那头神经兮兮的狮子和我们那个黑白朋友去哪儿了?
Marty? He's righ... Where did he go? He was right behind us.
马蒂? 他就在 他去哪儿了 他刚刚还在我们后面
He went back for Alex. He's going to get himself killed!
他回去找亚里克斯了 他会被吃掉的
Well, boys, our monochromatic friend's in danger.
哦 伙计们 我们的黑白朋友有难
Looks like we have a job to do.
看来我们有事可干了
Captain's log: Embarking into hostile environment.
船长日记 写:进入危险区域
Kowalski. We'll need to win the hearts and the minds of the natives.
科娃斯基 我们得去赢得当地居民的心
Rico. We'll need special tactical equipment.
里科 我们需要特殊的作战武器
We're going to face extreme peril.
我们将要面对异常严重的危险
Private probably won't survive.
二等兵可能会牺牲
Alex! Come out, Alex!
亚里克斯! 出来 亚里克斯!
The boat's here! We can go home!
有船来了! 我们可以回家了!
Alex! Alex! Alex! Alex! Alex!
亚里克斯! 亚里克斯! 亚里克斯! 亚里克斯! 亚里克斯!
Alex! Alex! Alex!
亚里克斯! 亚里克斯! 亚里克斯!
Alex!
亚里克斯!
Marty?
马蒂?
Snap out of it, Alex. The boat came back. We can get out of here.
振作起来 亚里克斯 船回来接我们了 我们可以离开这里了
We can go back to civilization, and everything will be like it used to be.
我们可以回到文明社会去 所有的事都会象以前那样的
Stay back.
别过来
Please.
求你了
I'm a monster.
我是个魔鬼
Alex, you're no monster. You're my friend.
亚里克斯 你不是魔鬼 你是我的朋友
We're a team. You and me, remember?
我们是一个团队 你和我 还记得吗?
I don't want to hurt you.
我不想伤害你
Alex.
亚里克斯
I ain't leaving without you.
你不走我也不走
Alex? I'm thinking of a song.
亚里克斯? 我在想一首歌
It's a wonderful song. I'm sure you're familiar with it.
一首很棒的歌 我知道你一定很熟悉这首歌
Start spreadin' the news
开始广布消息
I'm leaving today
今天我将离开
We are a great big part of it
我们组成了家
Come on, you know the words. Two little words.
嘿 你知道那个词的 那两个小小的字
Please don't make me sing this by myself.
求你了 别让我自己一个人唱这首歌
You really don't want to hear me sing this by myself.
你也不想听到自己独自唱这首歌的
Uh, Alex? Could you come out here for a minute?
呃 亚里克斯? 你可以出来一下吗?
Hey, Alex, a little help.
嘿 亚里克斯 我需要你帮点小忙
Help me!
救我!
Alex! Help!
亚里克斯! 救命啊!
Help me! Anybody, help me! Somebody!
救命啊! 有没有人可以救救我! 快来人啊!
Help!
救命啊!
- Melman? - That's right, baby.
- 梅尔曼? - 宝贝 是我
Run!
快逃!
- What's the plan? - This is the plan.
- 接下来怎么办? - 就这么办
- Fossa hungry. - Fossa eat.
- 伏狼饿了 - 伏狼要吃东西
This is the plan?
就只有这么办吗?
Fossa halt.
不许动 伏狼
Fossa ooh.
伏狼 噢
Fossa aaahh.
伏狼 啊
Fossa ooh.
伏狼 噢
Fossa aaahh.
伏狼 啊
Come and get it.
过来享用吧
Fossa.
伏狼
- Take that. - Fossa ow!
- 扁你 - 伏狼 噢
There's too many of them, skipper.
实在太多狼了 船长
It's been a real pleasure serving with you boys.
能和你们一起战斗到底真好
Alex?
亚里克斯?
That's my kill.
那是我的猎物
Mine.
我的
Alex hungry.
亚里克斯饿了
Alex eat.
亚里克斯要吃东西了
It's showtime.
到我们表演了
Thanks for not giving up on me.
谢谢你没有放弃我
Man, you almost gave me a heart attack. You can't just come sneak up on me.
伙计 你差点把我吓出心脏病来 不能因为你是头狮子
Just because you're a lion... Let go of me. Let go of me.
你就可以这么偷偷摸摸地来吓我 我们继续演下去 继续演
We're getting out of here. Guys, just go with me on this.
我们马上就可以脱困了 伙计们 只要你们和我配合就行
Like I said, it's showtime.
就想我说的 到表演的时间了
Mine.
我的
My kill.
我的猎物
They're all mine.
他们全都是我的
It's the king of the beasts! Oh, no!
野兽之王来了 哦 不!
- Don't eat me! - He's big and scary!
- 别吃我! - 他又大又面目狰狞!
Fear me! Savagery beyond comprehension.
让你们见识见识我的凶猛
- I am far too young to die! - You're a monster! A monster, I say!
- 我不想那么年轻就死! - 你真是个魔鬼! 魔鬼!
- And, you! - Me?
- 你! - 我?
Oh, you want some of this? Ooh! You better run for your lives.
你想尝尝这个吗? 嗯! 你们最好赶快去逃命
- Somebody call a cop! - He's psychotic!
- 赶快叫警察! - 他有神经病啊!
This is my territory. Understand?
这是我的领地 明白吗?
I never, ever want to see you on my turf again.
我再也不要见到你们在我的地盘上出现
Boo.
卜!
Yeah! You the cat!
呜呼! 你这只狮子!
Got my boy back!
我兄弟回来了!
I did it!
我成功了!
Give me some love! The plan worked! The plan worked! I'm very clever!
拥抱一下! 我的计划成功了! 计划成功了! 我可真聪明!
I'm the one, baby! Come on. Time to robot.
来 该跳机器舞了
I am very clever king.
我是聪明的国王
I am super genius.
我是超级天才
I am robot king of the monkey things.
我是猴子的机器国王
- Compute, compute. - So, what's for lunch?
- 计算 计算 - 那 午餐吃什么呢?
- Close those eyes. - Why do I have to?
- 闭上眼睛 - 为什么?
- Do it. - They're closed.
- 闭上嘛 - 都闭上了
- Tighter. - Yes, sir.
- 紧紧闭着 - 好的 长官
- No peeking. - They're closed.
- 不许偷看 - 闭着呢
Rico.
里科
Hai.
是
Open that hatch.
张开嘴巴
Fire in the hole. Now chew.
装好弹药 可以吃了
Chew like you mean it. Savor it.
认真咀嚼 仔细品尝味道
- And? - Well?
- 那么? - 不错吧?
Pretty good, right?
很好吧 对吧?
There's always Plan B.
如果不喜欢 这里还有备用的
This is better than steak.
这个比牛排好吃
I love it. I love it!
我爱吃 我真爱吃!
The kitty loves the fishy.
这狮子喜欢吃鱼哦
Well, I propose a toast.
让我们来干杯
Now, he may be a pain in the butt at times...
有的时候这家伙会让你屁股疼
And trust me, I know.
相信我说的 我身有体会
But this cat proved to me without a doubt
可这狮子也象我们证实了
that his heart is bigger than his stomach.
他有一颗宽大的心
- To Alex. - To Alex.
- 敬 亚里克斯 - 敬 亚里克斯
Enough! Stop it!
够了! 不许再吐了!
What do you think? Should we head back to New York?
你们怎么说? 我们要回纽约吗?
I don't know. I mean, this is your dream.
我不知道 我是说 这是你的梦
You sure you want to leave?
你确定你放弃?
I don't care where we are.
我才不在乎我们在哪里
As long as we're together, it doesn't matter to me.
只要我们可以在一起 哪里都行
Well, in that case...
那 如果是这样的话
Yo. Rico. I'll take 300 orders to go.
嘿 里科 我要300份外买
Hai.
嘿
But before you leave, I have an announcement to make.
你走之前 我有件事要宣布
So shut up, everyone, please. Thank you.
所以大家请安静一下 谢谢
After much deep and profound brain things inside my head,
在经过深思熟虑之后
I have decided to thank you
我决定要感谢你
for bringing peace to our home.
为我们的家园带来的和平
And to make you feel good,
为了好好感谢你
I'm going to give you this lovely parting gift.
我要送你这个可爱的告别礼物
No, I couldn't. Really, I can't take your crown.
不 我不能接受 真的 我不可以拿走你的皇冠
That's okay, I've got a bigger crown.
没事的啦 我弄了顶更大的
It's got a gecko on it.
上面还有只壁虎
Look at him shake. Go, Stevie, go!
看他跳舞 来 斯代维 来!
- Bye, little fuzzbuckets! - Thanks for everything!
- 再见了 小毛球! - 谢谢你做的所有的事
- So long! - Bye-bye, now.
- 再见! - 回见!
- Arrivederci. - Bye-bye.
- 再见 - 再见啦
- Toodle-oo! - See you later, crocodile.
- 再见了哦! - 回头见
Maurice, my arm is tired. Wave it for me.
莫里斯 我胳膊累了 帮我挥着
Faster, you naughty little monkey.
挥快点 淘气的小猴子
By the time we get back to New York, it'll be the middle of winter.
等我们到纽约的时候 已经是深冬了
So I was just thinking, why rush?
所以我在想 那我们还赶什么路呢?
Maybe we could make a few side stops along the way.
也许路上我们可以去些别的地方
- Maybe Paris. - You just read my mind.
- 比如巴黎 - 我正想说那里
I was thinking Spain. Run with the bulls.
我想去西班牙
- What about Fiji? - Canada. Can we?
- 要不斐济 - 可以去加拿大吗?
Cheap meds.
那儿药便宜
I wouldn't even mind coming back here sometime.
其实我不介意什么时候再回到这儿来
- I could do that. - You could say that again.
- 我也没问题 - 没问题
- Skipper? - I always wanted to go to Australia.
- 船长? - 我一直想去澳洲
Don't you think we should tell them that the boat's out of gas?
你觉得我们是不是要告诉他们那船没油了?
Nah.
不用
Just smile and wave, boys. Smile and wave.
只用微笑着挥手就是了 小伙子们 微笑着挥手